# RASHED RAHAT

# **INDUSTRY SKILLS**

HTML · CSS · Tailwind CSS · JavaScript ·

TypeScript · Node.js · React · Next.js

System Design ·

Performance Optimization ·

API Development and Integration

Responsive Design · Adaptive Design

Agile Methodologies (Scrum) · GIT

### **STRENGTHS**

#### Collaborative

Always willing to help, discuss, impart knowledge, and absorb new information from others. capable of working with multidisciplinary teams to produce a final product of the highest calibre.

#### Result-oriented

Enhanced team coherence with perfect precision by guaranteeing that advancement is directed appropriately.

### Detail-oriented

Always considering how to do things better and to the best of my abilities.

## Project management and prioritization

Before commencing a new project, I consistently allocate time for the entire team to collectively review, prioritize tasks, and assign deadlines to ensure timely completion and adherence to project timelines.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# Txam Web Architect

Ensured seamless experiences for 10,000+ concurrent student users at Shikho Technologies Bangladesh Ltd

### ★ Website Performance

Improved by 20-25% at Shikho Technologies Bangladesh Ltd

### ★ Page Load Time

Reduced by 30% at Misfit Technologies Ltd

### Learner First Award

Received at Shikho Technologies Bangladesh Ltd

# Senior Software Engineer, Front-End

+8801789093355 @ imrashedrahat@gmail.com

Ohaka, Bangladesh

## **SUMMARY**

Senior Front-End Developer with 5 years of experience in designing and building responsive web applications tailored for the educational technology and e-commerce sectors. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and User psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with improved code and design.

### **EDUCATION**

# **B.S. Software Engineering**

2015 - 2021

Dhaka, Bangladesh

AIU

- The major was focused on Web Development
- · In my senior year completed Practical Projects and Internship

CGPA 3.55 / 4.0

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Software Engineer, Front-End

12/2021 - Present

# Shikho Technologies Bangladesh Ltd

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Shikho is a top Bangladeshi edtech startup, transforming education with a localized digital learning system for all levels and professions.

- With my team, developed and maintained 3 high-traffic websites, > 1M quarterly unique users on each of them
- Assisted the junior developers with the design, development, deployment, and maintenance of all in-house products
- Stayed up to date on what needed to be updated in response to new release versions by adhering to the documentation
- Saved BDT 1 million per year in operating costs by integrating third-party tools that provide the functionality to integrate app analytics and marketing
- Collaborated with UX designers to implement user-friendly interfaces that improved user engagement & conversion rates and drove millions of additional revenue

#### Software Engineer, Front-End

03/2021 - 11/2021

#### Misfit Technologies Ltd

Dhaka, Bangladesh

A Singapore-based Design, Innovation, and Technology company operating in Myanmar, Bangladesh, USA, & Thailand since 2017, providing software solutions.

- Implemented a new responsive and mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 25%
- Enhanced adherence to company guidelines by enforcing web development standards, resulting in a 20% reduction in code review discrepancies
- Communicated with back-end developers for any front-end problematic issues

### Junior Software Engineer

06/2019 - 03/2021

### Workspace InfoTech Ltd

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Offers global IT services in software solutions, graphics design, web development, and hosting. Trusted for quality with experienced leadership.

- Completed training projects utilizing Node.js and React to create industry-standard web applications
- Performed testing, installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of various software programs
- Developed 200+ SQL queries in MySQL and MongoDB
- Contributed to the development of 20+ websites